Brandie Hatch | Data Scientist

Seattle Metro, Washington /in/brandiehatch • Github/brandiehatch

Reliable and collaborative designer turned data scientist with extensive experience in adult instruction as a Learning Specialist. My transferrable skills of communication, flexibility, patience, and authenticity are brought out when solving people-based problems for technical and non-technical audiences. I'm interested in how data science can solve for better learning opportunities.

Skills

Languages / Environments | Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Google Colab, Jupyter Notebook, Anaconda, Command Line, VS Code, Git, GitHub, Git Bash, Adobe Acrobat Pro

Packages | Pandas, NumPy, SKLearn, NLTK, BeautifulSoup, TensorFlow

Data Visualization | Seaborn, Plotly, Tableau, PowerBI

Modeling | Statistical Modeling, Regression Models, Classification Models, Time Series Analysis, Neural Networks, Image Classification

Statistics | Statistical Distributions, Bayesian Analysis, p-Values, Hypothesis Testing, Bayes Theorem

Human-based | Negotiation, Leadership, Consultation, Project Management (Agile, SAFe), Communication, Process Improvement

Projects

- Project 1: Standardized Test Analysis, exploration of a possible correlation between the California school districts with the most Free and Reduced-Price Meal (FRPM) participant and their scores on the ACT & SAT.
 Audience - Title I program leaders who determine funding or grant eligibility Tools - Python, Excel (03/2022)
- Project 2: Ames Housing Data and Kaggle Challenge, as the Black or African American populations rise in a census tract area, how does the sale price of houses in Ames, Iowa change?
 Audience - Iowa Real Estate Commission of real estate salespeople and brokers Tools - Python, US Census Data, Excel (04/2022)
- Project 3: Web APIs and NLP, how do the users of the Service Dogs Reddit and the Dog Training use language differently?
 Audience - Iowa Real Estate Commission of real estate salespeople and brokers Tools - Python, Excel, Reddit, Pushshift API (05/2022)

Relevant Professional Experience

Data Science Fellow 2022 – Present

General Assembly

 Gained technical foundation in Python, statistical modeling, SQL, machine learning for predictive modeling with varying algorithms from decision trees and random forests to natural language processing and neural networks.

 Completed multiple labs, quizzes, and projects along with a Capstone project to utilize machine-learning models to address a real-world data challenge.

Data Analyst 2020 – Present

Volunteers of America Western Washington

- Entered data and completed analysis for Hunger Prevention's COVID-19
 Emergency Food Lifeline distribution (2021) and Community Development Block
 Grant (CDBG) sponsored by Washington State Dept of Commerce and Work
 Force Snohomish County (2022).
- Analyzed the workflow for the Children's Snack Pack program to initiate grant writing and program growth for 2021-22 summer and school year services.
- Wrote grants and reports for the Washington State Department of Agriculture (WSDA) which gained \$50,000 to repair a food bank freezer and provide a tractor for the community garden that supplies fresh vegetables to the food bank.

Team Lead; Sr. Learning Experience Designer 2018 – 2020 **Instructional Systems Designer** 2016 – 2018

Boeing

- Administered Usability Studies to improve the user experience of performance support materials like job aids and knowledge articles to help employees use <u>Workday</u> cloud ERP. Results of studies: 29% increase in task completion, 63% decrease in average on-task minutes.
- Designed a web-based course which saved <u>Global Equity</u>, <u>Diversity</u>, <u>and</u> <u>Inclusion</u> specialists many business hours introducing board member roles and processes to 9 Enterprise Business Resource Groups with 152 Chapters.
- Negotiated with leaders to use hands-on activities for resume and interview skills during the Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCU) Boeing Scholar Bootcamp. Achieved 95% positive feedback from attendees and accolades from Diversity leaders for program innovation.
- Reported people bandwidth and project data in stoplight visualization.
- Performed people resourcing, project intake in a customer relationship management (CRM) system, budget and finance support, relationship building, and first tier support for people-based barriers.

- Designed, Developed, and Maintained Web-based Training for Manufacturing, Quality, and Safety, i.e., Autoclave Operations, Automated Equipment Safety, and Foreign Object Prevention (decreased cost of development by 80%).
- Blackboard Master Designer/Developer Functional Lead responsible for Instructional Designer and Developer courseware process standards to create courses in Blackboard.

Curriculum Developer

2014 - 2016

UW Medicine

- Created visualizations in Tableau to report Resident assessment results to the Assistant Director of Education and Director of Graduate Medical Education.
- Analyzed data from assessments and surveys to direct training program decisions
- Wrote evaluations to collect feedback data from course attendees

Education

Master of Education in Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri – Columbia, Cum Laude

chirolony of imeedan Colambia, Cam Laa

Bachelor of Science in EducationUniversity of Missouri - St. Louis, Magna Cum Laude

Certifications

Data Science Certification

General Assembly, Washington, DC

SAFe® for Teams, POPM Certification

Scaled Agile, Inc.

Consulting Skills Certification

Association for Talent Development

Leadership at All Levels Certificate

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

Agile Management Certificate

Villanova University

Data Visualization Certificate

University of Washington